Well, hello there. Thanks for joining me.
大家好欢迎观看这几个视频
I'm just going to pop in here and share some thoughts about reading research papers.
我来讲讲我阅读研究论文的经验
I remember when I got started doing academic work,
我还记得 当我开始搞学术研究时
reading a research paper felt like a daunting task.
阅读研究论文是一件让人头疼的事
I understood that reading a research paper meant sitting down with
阅读研究论文就是坐下来 泡杯茶
a cup of tea and reading the paper like I would a book from cover to cover,
像阅读图书一样从头读到尾
trying to absorb every word.
试着看懂每个字
When I accomplished this successfully,
成功读完一篇论文
it took me several hours.
需要好几个小时
When I failed, I would leave off in the middle,
读不下去的时候 我就会中途走开
often not remembering what I learned at the beginning.
经常不记得一开始学得是什么了
It must be said that being able to read and learn
说实话 能够快速读完并学习研究论文
from a research paper quickly comes with experience,
需要一定的经验
but also comes with experience in the specific field you're reading about.
但是还需要掌握论文所涉领域的经验
This is because research projects in
这是因为
each very specific niche field are highly interdependent.
每个具体领域的研究项目都是高度关联的
When you see that one paper is basically using the same method as another,
如果你看到一篇论文使用的方法和其他论文的方法一样
and you already understand that method,
并且你已经知道另一种方法
you can skip that entire method section.
那么就可以跳过整个方法部分
When you see that a paper references another paper for some idea,
如果你看到论文引用了其他论文的观点
and you've already read that other paper,
并且你已经读过另外这篇论文
because it's a very influential or so-called classic paper in the field,
因为另一篇是很有影响力或所谓的领域经典论文
you'll understand the reference.
你将明白引用的部分
There's no easy, quick way to gain this knowledge that I know of.
掌握这些知识没有什么捷径
It's one reason that developing expertise in a field is a long, hard one process.
原因之一是掌握领域技能是一个漫长而艰辛的过程
But there are some things to know about research papers and
但是有一些关于研究论文的知识和策略
some strategies you can take to make the process a little easier.
可以使论文阅读过程更轻松
I think the most important thing to remember is that you don't have to read everything.
我认为最重要的一点是不需要阅读所有内容
Research papers are designed in such a way as to show you,
研究论文的结构比较特殊
the reader, where to find different types of information.
便于作为读者的你找到不同类型的信息
Perhaps the second most important thing to remember
或许第二重要的技巧是
is that research papers are written by people.
研究论文是人写的
They are not infallible,
人无完人
they're not gospel, and they are not
孰能无过
perfect at communicating what they aim to communicate.
作者不一定善于表达想说的意思
What I mean to say is that if you don't understand something you're reading,
如果你不明白某个部分
it may be that you lack the background to understand it,
有可能是你缺少背景知识
but it may also be that the paper's author wrote it in a way that they understand it,
也有可能是论文作者的表达只有自己能理解
but not in a way that anyone else can understand it.
但是其他人不一定看得懂
Often, the author is writing to an audience that
经常 作者面向的读者
already knows the field, not to a new comer.
已经了解某个领域 并不是行业新手
Instead of banging your head against the wall, so to speak,
与其一直因为看不懂而想撞墙
or rereading the same section many times,
或者反复阅读同一部分
you may have to go elsewhere for a better understanding of the topic.
还不如寻找其他资料 帮助理解某个概念